Guide to the General Collection Manuscript Music Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
General Collection manuscript music miscellany
1600-2010
GEN MSS MUSIC MISC
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Linear Feet: ongoing; Total Boxes: ongoing; Other storage formats: oversize, bound volumes
Single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts relating to music. Materials are grouped under name headings. Within each name heading, materials are organized in three subgroups: Music, Correspondence, and Other Papers.
Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924 ( Quintets, piano, strings, no. 2, op. 115, C minor)
Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 ( Chanson de printemps)
Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 ( Cinq Mars)
Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 ( Chaste déesse)
Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 ( Rédemption, Ténèbres, arranged)
Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 ( Sapho)
Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947 ( Songs)
Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955 ( Judith)
Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919 ( Zazà, De l'aurore quittait)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Bacchus)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Cigale)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Enfants)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Espada)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Panurge)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( King of Lahore)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( 6e suite d'orchestre)
Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 ( Verter)
Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886 ( Marion Delorme)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Source information is recorded on folders and boxes. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Folders 1-12: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Oversize Folder 90 (Record album storage): ‡a Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts relating to music, acquired by the Beinecke Library from various sources and at various times. Some individual music manuscripts representing complete works are also cataloged in Yale University Library's on-line Public Access Catalog (Orbis), in addition to being listed here.
Materials are grouped alphabetically by name. Within each name heading, materials are organized in three subgroups: Correspondence, Music, and Other Papers. Within each subgroup, folders and volumes are listed by folder or volume title, except Music, which is arranged alphabetically by work title and subarranged by folder or volume title. Correspondence files contain outgoing letters from the name in the group heading to other correspondents, unless otherwise indicated. Music is written the composer's holograph, unless otherwise indicated.
To request materials listed here, please cite the Music Miscellany call number, written as GEN MSS MUSIC MISC, followed by the folder or volume number, including oversize designation if present, all of which appear at the beginning of the item description. For example, to obtain Folder 1 from the materials listed under Jules Massenet, request:
GEN MSS MUSIC MISC
Massenet, Jules, Folder 1
For Oversize Folder 1 from the materials listed under Jules Massenet:
GEN MSS MUSIC MISC
Massenet, Jules, Oversize Folder 1
For Volume 1 from the materials listed under Jules Massenet:
GEN MSS MUSIC MISC
Massenet, Jules, Volume 1
Ballets -- Excerpts -- Scores; Choruses; Composers; Hymns; Masses -- Scores; Motion picture music; Operas -- Excerpts -- Scores; Operas -- Excerpts; Operas -- Librettos; Operas -- Scores; Orchestral music -- Scores; Patriotic music; Pianists; Piano music; Piano quintets -- Excerpts -- Scores; Singers; Songbooks; Songs with piano; String quartets; Violinists; Vocal music -- Scores; Composers; Pianists; Singers; Violinists; Auber, D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871; Balfe, M. W. (Michael William), 1808-1870; Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869; Berners, Gerald Hugh Tyrwhitt-Wilson, Baron, 1883-1950; Boieldieu, A. (Adrien), 1775-1834; Bruneau, Alfred, 1857-1934; Burney, Charles, 1726-1814; Busoni, Ferruccio, 1866-1924; Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894; Charpentier, Gustave, 1860-1956; Chausson, Ernest, 1855-1899; Cherubini, Luigi, 1760-1842; David, Félicien, 1810-1876; Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918; Delibes, Léo, 1836-1891; Diaghilev, Serge, 1872-1929; Elman, Mischa, 1891-1967; Enesco, Georges, 1881-1955; Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946; Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924; Febvre, Frédéric-Alexandre, 1833-1916; Fétis, François-Joseph, 1784-1871; Feydeau, Georges, 1862-1921; Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883; Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936; Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893; Grétry, André-Ernest-Modeste, 1741-1813; Grove, George, 1820-1900; Guiraud, Ernest, 1837-1892; Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947; Halévy, F., 1799-1862; Halévy, Ludovic, 1834-1908; Hérold, Ferdinand, 1791-1833; Hervé, 1825-1892; Hofmann, Josef, 1876-1957; Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955; Hugo, Valentine, 1887-1968; Indy, Vincent d', 1851-1931; Isouard, Nicolo, 1775-1818; Jeritza, Maria, 1887-1982; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962; Kuhn, Lili; Lalo, Edouard, 1823-1892; Law, Andrew, 1749-1821; Lecocq, Charles, 1832-1918; Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919; Lind, Jenny, 1820-1887; Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886; Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945; Méhul, Etienne Nicolas, 1763-1817; Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931; Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Patti, Adelina, 1843-1919; Pierné, Gabriel, 1863-1937; Pizzetti, Ildebrando, 1880-1968; Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886; Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963; Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924; Reszke, Edouard de, 1853-1917; Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937; Roze, Marie Hippolyte Ponsin, 1846-1926; Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921; Sessions, Roger, 1896-1985; Spalding, Albert, 1888-1953; Spontini, Gaspare, 1774-1851; Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899; Sturges, Marietta; Sullivan, Arthur, 1842-1900; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901; Viardot-García, Pauline, 1821-1910; Wagner, Cosima, 1837-1930; Walton, William, 1902-1983; Wolff, Albert, 1835-1891; Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948; Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Alfano, Franco, 1875-1954
  - Music
    - Risurrezione. Vocal score
      Scope and Contents
      Opera, with libretto by Cesare Hanau, after Leo Tolstoy.
      Composed 1902-1903; first performed 1904.
      - Annotated score for Risurrezione, [1925?]; 1 vocal score (189 p.); 28 cm. (Box Volume 36)
        Printed vocal score in French translation by Paul Ferrier (Milan: Ricordi, c1910), with holograph annotations by the composer, most concerning tempo indications and cuts.
        Title page: Résurrection / tiré du roman de Léon Tolstoï; paroles de César Hanau; traduction française de M. Paul Ferrier; musique de Franco Alfano. Nouvelle édition.
        Manuscript annotation on a preliminary page: "Richard Barthélemy, revue et corrigée par l'Auteur, Monte Carlo, 20 juillet, 1925."
        Also accessible in the Yale online catalog.
        Immediate Source of Acquisition
        Purchased from Librairie Musicale Ancienne on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
- Auber, D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871
  - Correspondence
    - Auguste, Monsieur, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.); 19 cm. mounted on sheet, 39 cm. (Box OVERSIZE FOLDER 24)
      Brief ALS requesting tickets.
      Includes address leaf.
      In a series of leaves cut from an unidentified album. Items mounted on leaves are listed separately.
      Mounted on an leaf with letter from André Ernest Modeste Grétry.
      General
      Former group number: 2 AUBER, D. F. E.
      Purchased from Lisa Cox on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Scribe, Eugène, n.y. Dec 21; 1 item (2 p.); 19 cm. (Box Folder 201)
      Brief ALS sending the first act of an unidentified opera, referring to the second act, and mentioning "Monsieur de Normandie" and "M. Roller".
      Purchased from Julian Browning on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Bailly, Jean-Guy, 1925-
  - Music
    - Sonata, piano
      - "Sonate pour piano / Jean-Guy Bailly", 1967; 13 p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 34)
        Manuscript music, dated at Lyon.
        Purchased from Librairie Musicale Ancienne on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
- Balfe, M. W. (Michael William), 1808-1870
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (3 p.); 22 cm. (Box Folder 202)
      ALS to "Mon cher ami," about his opera Këolanthé, or The Unearthly Bride.
      Former group number: 3 BALFE, M. W.
      Gift.
- Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869
  - Correspondence
    - Barbier, Auguste, 1864 Nov 17; 1 item ( 2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 203)
      From Barbier: ALS giving his new address and responding to an invitation from Berlioz.
      Former group number: 4 BERLIOZ, HECTOR
      Purchased from Laurin, Guilloux, Buffetaud on the Library Associates Endowment Fund, 1997.
    - Bay, Jean de, 1856 Jun 22; 1 item (1 p.); 14 cm. (Box Folder 204)
      From Bay: ALS offering congratulations on Berlioz's election to the Institut.
    - Chasles, Philarète, n.y. Oct 11; 1 item (1 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 205)
      From Chasles: brief humorous ALS.
    - Chenavard, Paul Marc Joseph, 1856 Jun 27; 1 item (1 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 206)
      From Chenavard: ALS offering congratulations on Berlioz's election to the Institut.
    - David, Ferdinand, 1853, 1854; 3 items. (Box Folder 207)
      Two ALS, Paris, regarding the reception of Berlioz's music in Germany.
      Accompanied by ALS, n.d., 3 rue Vivienne, from Marie Moke-Pleyel to Mr. Gonzales, apologizing for missing his visit.
      Purchased from Moirandat Company AG on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1997.
    - Deschamps, Antoni, 1844 Oct 15; 1 item (1 p.); 21cm. (Box Folder 208)
      From Deschamps: ALS consisting of a poem titled "Souvenir de M. Félicien David, à Hector Berlioz".
    - Legouvé, Ernest, [1837], n.d.; 2 items. (Box Folder 209)
      From Legouvé: ALS, dated 1837 Dec 7 in an unidentified hand, about Berlioz's Requiem; and ALS, n.d., introducing Armand Béhic.
    - Sayn-Wittgenstein, Carolyne de, 1866 Jan 11; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 210)
      ALS, Paris, in response to her letters.
    - Soulié, Frederic, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.); 21cm. (Box Folder 211)
      From Soulié: brief ALS proposing a meeting.
    - Wailly, Léon de, n.y. Mar 21; 1 item (3 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 212)
      From Wailly: ALS expressing gratitude.
  - Music
    - Temple universel
      For double chorus (TTBB, TTBB) and organ, with text by Jean-François Vaudin.
      Composed and published 1861.
      - Fragment from Le temple universel, [1861?]; 1 ms. score fragment ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 35)
        Fragment of a score, holograph, with revisions and printer's markings. The music appears on pages 13-14 of the score published by L'Orphéon in 1861.
        Purchased from Pierre Berès on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
- Berners, Gerald Hugh Tyrwhitt-Wilson, Baron, 1883-1950
  - Correspondence
    - Newman, Ernest, 1920-25; 4 items. (Box Folder 213)
      Four ALS, with envelopes, including references to a virginal built by Arnold Dolmetsch.
      Former group number: 5 BERNERS, BARON
      Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, 2000 May 26, lot 037) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
  - Restricted Fragile
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - Folder 213, 1925; 1 item. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 6)
- Bishop, Henry R. Henry Rowley, Sir, 1786-1855
  - Music
    - God is our refuge in distress
      Former group number: 51 BISHOP, HENRY R.
      - "God is our refuge in distress = Ein' feste Burg ist unser Gott: Corale: / composed (at Cobourg, A.D. 1530 [i.e. 1527]) by Martin Luther; arranged by Sir Henry R. Bishop", [ca. 1844?]; 1 ms. score ([7] p.); 31 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 18)
        Autograph manuscript score of an arrangement by Henry R. Bishop of Martin Luther's hymn Ein feste Burg ist unser Gott. The score is written in an unknown hand, with the cover signed by the arranger. Arranged for four voices (SATB) and keyboard accompaniment.
        Title from cover.
        Gift of Philip Neufeld, in honor of H. W. Liebert.
- Boieldieu, François Adrien, 1775-1834
  - Correspondence
    - Cotelle, Monsieur, 1828 Jun 30; 1 item (3 p.); 20 cm., mounted on sheet, 39 cm. (Box OVERSIZE FOLDER 24)
      ALS to Cotelle, Paris, possibly Alexandre Cotelle of Janet & Cotelle, concerning purchase of books for Boieldieu's son.
      In French. English translation in an unidentified hand on adjoining sheet.
      Former group number: 6 BOIELDIEU, FRANCOIS ADRIEN
- Boyce, William, 1711-1779
  - Music
    - Trio sonatas, violins, violoncello, continuo
      Former group number: 7 BOYCE, WILLIAM
      - "Twelve [sonatas] for two violins and violoncello with a thorough bass for the harpsichord / by Dr Boyce", [17--]; 1 v. of music ([34] p.); 28 cm. (Box Folder 214)
        Copyist's manuscript of the first violin part from Boyce's twelve trio sonatas. The ninth trio sonata, which appears last in order, is incomplete. The twelve sonatas are designated as "No. 7" on the title page and in caption titles.
        Title written as: Twelve sonata's for two violins and violoncello with a thorough bass for the harpsichord composd by Dr Boyce.
        Gift of Edward Allen Canfield, 1981.
- Brace, Joab, 1781-1861
  - Music
    - Music book, 1803-1857; 1 v. of manuscript music (178 p.); 11 x 20 cm. (Box Volume 65)
      Manuscript music book, 1803, possibly in the hand of Joab Brace, containing hymns, most without texts. One hymn is dated 1857 October 15.
      Title devised by cataloger.
      Preliminary page: Joab Brace, New Haven, Yale College, April 22, 1803.
      Source unknown.
- Bruneau, Alfred, 1857-1934
  - Correspondence
    - Marty, Georges, 1907, 1908; 2 items. (Box Folder 215)
      ALS, 1907 Jul 5, thanking Marty for a journal; and ALS, 1908 May 22, concerning Messidor.
      Former group number: 8 BRUNEAU, ALFRED
      Purchased from Jan Ceuleers (Romantic Agony Book Auctions, Cat. 14, 2001 Mar 16 sale, lot 347) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, [1891 Nov 8]; 1 item (1 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 216)
      ALS, with date in an unidentified hand, to "Mon cher Gabriel," concerning the premiere of Le rêve in Brussels.
- Burney, Charles, 1726-1814
  - Correspondence
    - Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1778 Jan 11; 1 item (3 p.); 23 cm. (Box Folder 217)
      ALS, London, about the education of Burney's son and music instruction for Piozzi's daughter, and referring to Samuel Johnson.
      With typed transcript.
      Former group number: 9 BURNEY, CHARLES
      Purchased from Gottlieb on the Hubert Amer McGuire Memorial Fund, 1951.
    - Walker, Joseph Cooper, 1793 Jul 1; 1 item (4 p.); 26 cm. (Box Folder 218)
      ALS, London, discussing Asian music, Walker's Hints for a system of education for a female orphan-house, and Burneys' Memoirs of the life and writings of the Abate Metastasio.
      Purchased from W. R. Benjamin on the Hubert Amer McGuire Memorial Fund, 1953.
- Busoni, Ferruccio, 1866-1924
  - Correspondence
    - Boghen, Felice, 1921 Jun 14; 1 item (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box Folder 219)
      ALS, with envelope, to Boghen, Florence, thanking him for sending reviews of Busoni's music.
      Former group number: 10 BUSONI, FERRUCCIO
      Purchased from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. (Sotheby's, 2000 Dec 8, lot 16) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Chabrier, Emmanuel, 1841-1894
  - Music
    - Muscadins
      Opera, with libretto by Jules Claretie and Armand Silvestre.
      Composed 1880-1881; incomplete.
      - Sketches, [circa 1880?]; 1 ms. score fragment ([2] p.); 28 x 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 37)
        Sketches in short score, holograph, possibly for Les muscadins.
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified fragment, undated; 1 ms. score fragment ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 36)
        Fragment of a score, holograph, for unidentified voice or instrument and keyboard.
        Purchased from Demarest on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
- Champommier, -----
  - Music
    - Fureur de Saül
      Former group number: 11 CHAMPOMMIER
      - "Fureur de Saül: cantate / paroles de E. M. T.; musique de Champommier", 1876; 1 ms. score (118 p.); 36 cm. (Box Volume 9)
        Score, including parts for orchestra and piano reduction, written in manuscript in an unidentified hand. Laid in are a manuscript vocal score of the final scene and a printed libretto with corrections in manuscript.
- Charpentier, Gustave, 1860-1956
  - Correspondence
    - Gangnat, Robert, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 220)
      ALS to Gangnat, of the Societe des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques, discussing claims made by Saint-Pol-Roux concerning rights to the libretto of Charpentier's opera Louise.
      Former group number: 12 CHARPENTIER, GUSTAVE
      Purchased from Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
  - Music
    - Impressions d'Italie
      Suite for orchestra.
      Composed 1889-90; published 1892.
      - Quotation from Impressions d'Italie, undated; 1 item ([1] sheet); 11 x 18 cm., affixed to sheet, 32 cm. (Box Folder 395)
        Quotation, autograph manuscript, signed.
        Purchased from Christie's (Rome sale, 2001 December 13, lot 385), on the Library Associates Endowment Fund, 2002.
- Chausson, Ernest, 1855-1899
  - Correspondence
    - Godet, Robert, n.d.; 1 item (4 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 221)
      ALS concerning an audition by singer Madame de Ciana.
      Former group number: 13 CHAUSSON, ERNEST
- Cherubini, Luigi, 1760-1842
  - Other Papers
    - Receipt, 1831 Feb 26; 1 item (1 sheet); 12 x 19 cm. (Box Folder 222)
      Receipt, Paris, holograph, signed, for money used to purchase a solfege for a student at the Paris Conservatoire. Appended is a receipt for money for additional music, written in an unidentified hand.
      Former group number: 13 CHERUBINI, LUIGI
      Purchased from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. (Sotheby's, 2000 Dec 8, lot 67) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Cras, Jean, 1879-1932
  - Music
    - Ames d'enfants
      Composed 1918, in three versions: for piano, six hands and four hands, and for orchestra.
      Cras, composer and officer in the French navy, composed Ames d'enfants for his daughters, Isaure, Colette, and Monique, while commander of the ship Commandant Bory.
      Former group number: 14 CRAS, JEAN
      - "Ames d'enfants: pour orchestre / Jean Cras", 1918 Feb-Mar; 1 ms. score (60 p.); 39 cm. (Box Volume 10)
        Score, ith corrections and conductor's annotations, signed and dated at end, "A bord du Commandant-Bory, Vallona, 1918 Feb." An additional date, 1918 Mar 29, appears at the end of the first part.
        Pl. no.: [E.M.S.?] 6563 (manuscript annotation for Éditions Maurice Senart).
        Contents: I. Pures. II. Naïves. III. Mystérieuses.
    - Journal de bord
      Suite for orchestra, in three movements corresponding to sections of a ship's log.
      Composed 1927.
      - "Journal de bord: suite symphonic / Jean Cras", 1927 November 12; 1 ms. score ([circa 75] p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 38)
        Holograph score, with revisions, conductor's markings, and printer's markings, signed and dated on board "La Provence." Accompanied by a page from a ship's log, printed form completed in holograph, signed.
        Title from caption.
        Publishers number 7636 (manuscript printer's annotation).
        Purchased from Les Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Polyphème. Vocal score
      Opera, with a libretto by Albert Samain, originally in four acts.
      Composed 1912-1918; Prix de la Ville de Paris 1921.
      - "Polyphème", 1912-1921; 1 ms. vocal score (264 p.); 36 cm. (Box Volume 11)
        Vocal score of a version in three acts, with corrections and performance annotations. The score is signed and dated at end, 1912 Aug, Toulon-1915 Christmas, Paris. Other annotations are dated 1913-1921. "Interlude: Le sommeil de Galatée," unpaged and inserted between scenes 1 and 2, act I, is dated 1921 Nov 4. Two fragments of a page are laid in.
        Pl. no.: [E.M.S.] 4701 (manuscript annotation for Éditions Maurice Senart).
- Darling, Samuel, 1751-1842
  - Music
    - Samuel Darling's book, [circa 1765]; 1 v. of manuscript music (96 p.); 10 x 20 cm. (Box Volume 67)
      Manuscript music book containing hymn tunes, and hymns and songs for four voices. Many hymns are identified by tune names or Psalm numbers, and some include texts. A few are by "Billings," possibly American composer William Billings.
      Title from page stub.
- David, Félicien, 1810-1876
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.); 23 cm., mounted on sheet, 39 cm. (Box OVERSIZE FOLDER 24)
      ALS to "Monsieur," requesting tickets, with an annotation in an unidentified hand referring to [Louis Désiré?] Véron.
      Former group number: 15 DAVID, FELICIEN
- Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918
  - Correspondence
    - Louys, Pierre, [1902 Oct 15]; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 223)
      ALS, Paris, regarding rehearsals for "Pelleas et Melisande."
      Former group number: 16 DEBUSSY CLAUDE
    - Louÿs, Pierre, 1898, n.d.; 2 items. (Box Folder 224)
      Two envelopes addressed in holograph to Louÿs: Cairo, Egypt, corrected to 147 Bd. Malherbes, Paris, 1898 Apr 21; and no place, undated.
      Purchased from William Reese Co. on the Library Associates Fund Fund.
  - Music
    - Jeux; arr.
      Ballet, with libretto by Waslaw Nijinsky.
      Composed 1912-1913; first performed 1913; published 1912 (piano score), 1914 (full score).
      - "Jeux: poeme danse de Nijinsky / musique de Claude Debussy; partition pour piano reduite par l'auteur", [ca. 1912]; 1 score (41 p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 19)
        Engraved proof (Paris: Durand, 1912), signed and annotated in Russian by Waslaw Nijinsky.
        With signed inscription by Serge Lifar on cover: "Partition de Waslaw Nijinsky avec les notations de Diaghilev, de Nijinsky de Debussy de Bakst."
        Cover title.
        Publisher's stamp on cover.
        T.p. and p. 1-2 lacking.
        Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's London, 1997 May 16, lot 151) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Delibes, Léo, 1836-1891
  - Correspondence
    - Erlanger, Camille, [1890] Dec 7; 1 item (8 p.); 17 cm. (Box Folder 225)
      ALS, Paris, giving advice to Erlanger, a student of Delibes and winner of the Prix de Rome. Delibes discusses works of Erlanger, including Saint Julien l'hospitalier, and refers to Jules Massenet, Camille Saint-Saens, Gustave Charpentier, and other musicians.
      Former group number: 17 DELIBES, LEO
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (4 p.); 14 cm. (Box Folder 227)
      ALS to "Mon cher ami," concerning performances by Rose Caron and Jacques Isnardon, and referring to Ambroise Thomas.
      Purchased from on Lisa Cox the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, n.y. Apr 2; 1 item (3 p.); 17 cm. (Box Folder 226)
      ALS to "Cher Monsieur," an unidentified composer, thanking him for the dedication of a Gloria in excelsis Deo.
      Dated "samedi 2 avril".
  - Music
    - Mélodies, 1. recueil. Eglogue
      Song, with text by Victor Hugo.
      Published in Mélodies, 1. recueil, 1863.
      - "Eglogue / Victor Hugo", [circa 1863]; 1 ms. score ([3] p.); 28 x 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 39)
        Holograph score, signed with initials.
        Purchased from Les Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Mélodies, 2. recueil. Faut-il chanter?
      Song, with text by Borelli.
      Published in Mélodies, 2. recueil.
      - "L'oiseau m'a dit, faut-il chanter?", 1890 August 20; 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 27 x 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 40)